Jacob Libby

jacobnlibby@gmail.com | (207) 807-6444 | linkedin.com/in/jacob-libby-416b99149 | github.com/JacobLibby | jacoblibby.com

SUMMARY

Highly-skilled software engineer with a combined 7 years of computer science teaching and data standardization experience. Pioneered improvements of data pipelines and designed ETL code, resulting in an 80% reduction in delivery time and enthusiastic satisfaction from the company's top 3 largest and most profitable clients. Integral in ongoing process of national bank's full data pipeline migration. Passionate about analyzing data and constructing data pipelines to create tangible impact.

HIGHLIGHTED SKILLS

 Pyth 	or
--------------------------	----

C++

Github

Zena

• SAS

WinSCP

VMWare

- SQL
- AWS
- pytorch
- Azure DevOps
- Filezilla

Scrum Master

- ъ .
- Bash

- Machine Learning
- Data Ops
- scikitlearn
- SOL Server
- AWS Glue
- Microsoft Suite

- Artificial Intelligence
- CI/CD
- tensorflow
- Transact-SQL
- Snowflake
- Command Line

Languages: Python, SQL (PostgreSQL, PrestoSQL, SQLite), Bash, Ruby, R, Javascript, C, C++, Assembly **Technologies:** Machine Learning, pandas, sci-kit learn, numpy, pytorch, Jinja, Flask, Rails, React, BigQuery, GCP, Apache Beam, Airflow

Tools: Github, Amazon Web Services (AWS: S3, Athena), CI/CD, APIs, Jira, Confluence, NVIM, Tableau

EDUCATION

Certifications and Independent Coursework

2024 - Present

- IBM Python Data Science | Python, Data Science
- BigQuery for Big Data Engineers | BigQuery, Google Cloud Platform, Web Console, Python Client Library
- Odin's Full Stack Ruby on Rails & JavaScript | Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, React, NodeJS
- MIT OCW's Performance Engineering | C, Algorithms, Optimization, Parallel Programming, Assembly

Wheaton College, Norton, MA

2018 - 2022

- B.A. in Computer Science, Dean's List 2018 2022
- B.A. in Mathematics, Dean's List 2018 2022

Magna Cum Laude, GPA: 3.73/4.00

Magna Cum Laude, GPA: 3.72/4.00

EXPERIENCE

Data Engineer

Huntington Bank, Minnetonka, MN

Sep 2024 - Present

- Design, develop, and optimize data orchestration through processing pipelines and workflows using Zena, AWS, SQL Server, Snowflake, and RedPoint
- Provide production support, responding rapidly to incidents and automating areas of improvement
- Perform data wrangling and exploration to support business needs
- Facilitates stand-up and other Agile meetings as a secondary Scrum Master

- Designed and implemented Python, SQL, Jinja, and Bash ETL/ELT code to standardize client medical claims and member data for analyses, reducing delivery time by up to 80%
- Led standardization and dashboarding of healthcare data, resulting in multiple multimillion dollar contracts
- Wrote well-documented code for over 5 clients, including the company's 3 most profitable clients
- Cultivated cross-team collaboration with project managers, data scientists, data analysts, improving communication and streamlining the implementation of client and team feedback

CS Tutor and Teaching Assistant Wheaton College, Norton, MA

Jan 2020 - May 2022

- Guided over 70 students through concepts in Python, SQL, C++, C, Data Structures, Algorithms, OOP
- Recommended programming and critical analysis strategies, significantly improving student performance
- Analyzed student code 1-on-1 and counseled implementations to optimize time and memory efficiencies
- Articulated logistics of over 20 programming assignments, ensuring understanding of project requirements
- Fostered relationships with tutees, creating an environment of trust and inclusion

FabLab Technician

Wheaton College, Norton, MA

Aug 2019 - May 2022

- Trained over 100 students and faculty on makerspace equipment (3D printing, laser cutting, CNC milling)
- Assisted students in creating portfolio websites and thorough documentation for 15 projects
- Supported 30 students enrolled in FabAcademy in circuitry, soldering, Fusion, KiCad, and web design

Treasurer - WCCS Radio

Wheaton College, Norton, MA

Jan 2019 - May 2021

- Kept records of all expenditures using the organization's portals and Microsoft Excel
- Created annual budget and applied for funding, culminating in an over \$20,000 annual budget
- Orchestrated event planning with vendors, faculty, and students
- Regularly provided financial reports to members of the organization

Apple Repair Technician

ESPO Corporation, Portland, ME

June 2021 - July 2021

- Diagnosed and troubleshot customers' technical issues and performed hardware repairs in a timely fashion
- Created and maintained accurate inventory records of all computer components
- Handled and processed the incoming and outgoing orders and shipping procedures

A/V Technician

Casco Bay High School, Portland, ME

Dec 2014 - May 2018

- Trained students and faculty on audio and video equipment for meetings, events, and shows
- Maintained and operated live sound equipment and projectors for over 120 live events